[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet Museum of
hologography
hello this is feisty Freitas and welcome
to holotalk the internet's laser and
holography talk show our toll-free
number is
[Music]
1-800-458-3525 or you can send an email
to holotalk
holoworld.com we've got telephone calls
we've got emails we've got special
guests coming up so thank you for tuning
in and let's get this week's show on the
road
hello this is Frankie Freitas and
welcome to another week of holotalk
we're recording this live at the
Discovery Center of Science and
Technology and fairly soon you'll be
able to stop by and see us doing the
show live in commend
ant that participate in the show put you
on the air if you want
in any case if you remember last week I
mentioned we had a
story about a holography exhibit that's
going to be coming into the air in by
the area I mean if you live in the New
York Philadelphia Baltimore
see Corridor and take that West over to
Harrisburg and make a rectangle out of
that if you're somewhere in that area
this holography exhibit is going to be a
very easy trip for you to go to and see
and this is going to be a major exhibit
for lasers and hologram
latest news that I have as far as an
update on this is if this show does
indeed come together I don't think
there's any contract signed on this yet
but if the show does indeed come
together it's going to be this summer
so this summer we've got a major laser
and holography traveling exhibit that's
going to come into this area now
if you'd like to have more information
on this and I will keep you up to date
as I find out information you need to
send an email
two
good
at holyworld.com that's exhibit at
holyworld.com I will take your email I
have a special folder made for all the
emails that's coming through on the show
and as I get information I will send
that information out to you but I'll
also give updates on the show too if you
want to get your information that way
but if you do send me an email you will
get it before everybody else
okay this is our off week as you know
every weekend
shows on the air but not every week do
we have guests we have guests every
other week and the shows in between we
usually try to get caught up on some of
the questions
that come true either on a total
toll-free line or
by email
last week's guest was Brian Monahan and
Brian has a company Pennsylvania Pulp
and Paper and they he came on and told
us about desktop holography they're
working with them
desktop system there and going to a
hollow printer
next week Our Guest is going to be Jimmy
Wolford and Jimmy has a company down in
Panama they're involved with the
security holography so we'll be we'll be
something find out a little bit about
his company and maybe get a couple
questions answered about how Holograms
are used in the security industry as
well so you want to tune in for that
that's Jimmy Jimmy Woodford okay we're
going to move on and do a few email
questions
and let's see what we have first
okay our first question is from Mike and
it's a two-part two parts you know let's
go into the first part here and Mike
says I'm about to shoot a split beam
reflection hologram the book calls for a
light reading before I shoot it
I got a little confused about the Light
reading because there are two beans
hitting the object
do I take the reading as I would on a
single beam reflection concentrating on
the reference beam and ignoring the
object beam
or you wouldn't have two games if you
were doing a single beam reflection but
I know what you mean there or is there
another way to do it now go in there and
take readings of both your object and
reference beam and the way you do the
reference beam is typically you just
take your probe and point it down
towards the lens or whatever you're
using the angle that that reference beam
is coming in
and move it around the plate area you
can hold it right in the plane of the
plane holder move it around and get an
average reading you know you're going to
have a hot spot probably right in the
middle if you don't have the bean spread
out but you want to spread that beam out
enough but you're not going to see that
much of a variation from the center of
where your hologram is going to be
recorded out to the edges so you're
trying to spread that area out as much
as possible you lose a lot of power
and if you don't have a lot of power to
spare then you don't want to spread that
beam out too much but you want to try
and avoid that hot spot in the middle
you're going to need your object out of
place to do this you got to get your
hand right now
right down hold that probe in the plane
of the plate holder now for the object
being just put your object back in there
take the probe go around the other side
pulling it toward the object right in
the plane of where you're filming your
Plate's going to be and just go around
that object and and get a number of
different readings
you want to try and keep your ratios for
split beam reflection hologram being
made directly from an object probably
two to one where two is the reference
being reading and one is the object so
if you've got a 40 reading on your scale
for reference beam you want to try and
get a 20
that's the maximum for your object
uh second part of the question is I am
setting up for split beam reflection
hologram and the book calls for 90 10
beam splitter but it does not say
whether the reference beam or object
beam should have the greater intensity
once again the reference beam always has
the greater intensity and you know you
have to take with what you read in the
books with a grain of salt because
they're they're giving
um just generalizations you know I mean
you don't absolutely have to have a 90
10 B Spooner I I've never had a variable
beam splitter I just never spent the
money for them I have a selection of the
little beam Splitters about the sides of
microscope slides some of them were 90
10 75 25 60 40 50 50. and I will use you
know whatever beam splitter I need to
get the ratio that I need
now what's going to determine that is
the fact of how bright or how much light
your object is going to reflect
if you have a bright object that's
painted white or something porcelain or
something like that that's obviously
going to reflect a lot more laser light
than say an object that's black or dark
so the what's going to determine what
beam splitter you use when you do your
setup so that you can fall within that
ratio sometimes you have to give more
light to the object beam in order to
bring that up if you've got a dark
and other times if your object is
reflecting a lot of laser light you can
actually cut that object being back and
give more light to the reference and
once again before I close down on this
question I just want to let you know
that there are a number of different um
formulas that you can use where you plug
different numbers in to figure out what
your exposure time is going to be and
they go by the intensities and the
amount of energy that's being applied to
the Emulsion over given amount of time
but for all practical purposes like with
the holography handbook published by
Ross books and you just take the if
you've got your ratio set up properly
you take your reference beam reading and
that's what you use on the chart to
figure
time you get for your exposure
exposed just a reminder to you the
listeners you can call your questions in
on our toll-free number that number is
1-800-458-352
525 there's no charge for the call
nothing will show up on your phone bill
and I would love to use your voice on
the air and you can also send email to
holotalk holoworld.com send your
question in there I'll read your
question
so either way it's okay it seems like
email seems to be the Preferred Choice
which I guess only makes sense since
most people only have one line and if
you're listening to the show you can
send an email right away if you're
online
without logging off and then picking up
the phone
um got an email from Mark Diamond
and Mark wrote to me if a couple weeks
ago someone sent a question in as to
when was the first hologram used on a
magazine cover and I gave the answer of
National Geographic in 1984 with the
American Eagle
and and Mark says
let's see uh okay here we go the first
hologram to appear in a publication not
actually on a cover
was in 1967 it was World Books science
year this was actually a transmission
type and a red filter was provided to
clean up the light of a flashlight or
slide projector with which you could
then transaminate the hologram
he says he has several of these
Holograms and the Hologram was made at
conductron affiliated with McDonald
Douglas
in the late 1960s and I remember this
hologram I remember this hologram that
does go back quite a way Mark's got a
website that website's
www.diamondimages.com and diamond images
is one word and once again it's www
diamond
income go over and check out his his
website I have one of his Holograms of
Billy Gillespie I have his daily
Gillespie hologram it's pretty cool
okay our next question
uh no name on this email there's an
email address but I won't give that but
there was no name signed to it and this
person says I am an amateur and I've
just started holography
I've done eight Holograms none showing
an image but there is a fuzzy
multi-colored thing showing some depth
but then a dark shadow in the same shape
on every one of my Holograms
you know every hologram holds an answer
if there's something wrong with your
hologram let's start off by saying that
you do a hologram and you say there's
something wrong with it every hologram
has its own answer as to what
problem is and after you've done
holography for a number of years you can
look at a hologram and tell immediately
what it is
a lot of times it's very hard from a
description to tell what it is without
seeing the actual hologram and I think
this is the case here I really can't
tell what this is that you're talking
about without seeing a hologram so if
you're listening to the show
if you could take a picture of the
Hologram and send that along or better
yet if you have a website or internet
access to a web page just upload the
jpeg of the Hologram so maybe a few of
us in holography can log on and take a
look at it we can tell you what's going
wrong it's a shame you've done eight and
you're still getting that but from what
you've explained right here in the email
I can't really tell what it is that that
could
problem
so if you want to email me again let me
know if there's some way I can take a
look at it or if you want to put it up
on the web a bunch of us that are
involved with holography can take a look
at it and we can get back to you as far
as what we think
that would be good corrective measures
for that hologram okay we have someone
that's writing that's confused in
England and this guy's name's well I
can't say it's a guy it's Chris I guess
it could be a young lady as well
Chris Wright is it true when a hologram
shatters the whole image can be seen in
all the broken parts if so why does this
happen well this is something a lot of
people always talk about the fact you
can take a hologram break it up into a
thousand pieces and each one of the
pieces contain the entire holographic
image that's true to a point and we've
had this question a number of other
times on the show
and what actually happened is you can
see the image this happens best with a
laser transmission hologram because
laser transmission Holograms are made
and usually more than likely the the
object is quite a bit of distance in the
holographic plate compared to a
reflection hologram where you have the
object as close to the plate as possible
when that object is located at quite a
bit of distance from the plate and you
break that plate up you can still see
the whole object but you see it through
the perspective of wherever that piece
of glass came from so say let's just say
the simplified things you burnt the holy
gram up into four pieces
you've got your upper left you've got
your upper right you've got your lower
left you've got your lower weight now if
you picked up the upper left hand piece
if you look through that piece you would
be able to see the entire object however
you'd see it from that perspective
and if you picked up the lower right
hand corner
and look through that piece of glass
you'd still see the whole object but
you'd see it from the perspective of the
lower right corner so that's how that
works
okay we have a email from Francis and
Francis says hello I'm a junior in high
school I'm very interested in holography
I'm wondering if there are any colleges
where I could major in holography or at
least take some classes and if not what
would be a good major if I wanted to get
into holography some sort of physics
thank you for your time Francis uh
Francis I'm not aware of any majors in
holography I think the Art Institute in
Chicago has a art major in holography
while you're listening to the show
because I I'm just going to take for
granted that you're going to tune in or
listen to your answer if you go to the
education wing
site you'll see a listing of different
courses that you can take for holography
if anyone out there office courses
please email me and I'll be happy to put
you on a list so people can get in touch
with you as well Royal College of Art in
London I believe also has a degree
program and in photography
but physics would be the strong point I
would imagine if you wanted to get
involved with holography but I'm not
quite sure how it's approached from the
art and I know there are a number of
different artists who are involved with
holography and they
a lot of them don't approach it from the
Science and Technology standpoint as
much as they approach it from the
creative standpoint of an artist so it
depends on what you would want to get
out of holography in the end
certainly what it is you should or how
you should approach holography as part
of your studies
next question this is from another Mike
uh I am doing an experiment on
holographs
Holograms Mike holograms for physics
I don't know of any experiment to do if
you have any I would appreciate any help
you could give me thanks a lot I
appreciate it Mike
for science fair projects you probably
have a lot more to choose from if you
were to do experiments with lasers than
with Holograms unless you plan on doing
some sort of an experiment where you're
going to make your own Holograms once
the Holograms are made I can't really
think of too many things of doing a
science fair project with them now you
could do a number of different
experiments of course you could get
Holograms and illuminate them with
different lights
find out what the result would be from
different lights Illuminating the
Hologram and
of course lightning wavelengths you're
going to take a look and see what
different wavelengths do when you
illuminate already made Holograms with
the different wavelengths and you can
compare that with reflection Holograms
and white light transmission Holograms
even in Boss telegrams would probably be
easiest for you
but outside of actually making Holograms
just offhand I can't think of very many
science fair projects you could do with
already made Holograms you have a much
better choice going with lasers and
doing a science fair project working
with lasers
all right so that just about Catches Us
up with our email questions don't forget
you can send your questions in the
telephone number is
1-800-458-3525 that's a toll-free number
there's no charge it doesn't show up in
your bill to leave your question on the
voicemail and we'll use your voice on
the on the air or you can send your
question to holotalk at hollowworld.com
and I'll read the question and answer it
on the air for you this was our off week
next week Our Guest is going to be Jimmy
Wofford and he's going to be filling Us
in on how Holograms are used in the
security
Panama
so this is Frankie Francis thank you for
tuning in we were doing this live at the
Discovery Center of Science and
Technology we'll be doing it live here
every week I also have a new radio show
that's going to come up we're going to
record it here live every Sunday it's
going to be a weekly science technology
broadcast we're going to have area
students involved with it we'll be doing
that live here as well
if you'd like more information about
coming out and seeing the show or even
stopping by I'll put you on here no
problem with that send an email to me at
hello talk at holyworld.com and just
marking that email I'd like to come out
and see the show being done so I'll send
an email back and give you some more
information on that so thank you very
much for tuning in this is Frankie
phrase for whole talk and we'll see you
next week